A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Correspondence of Sheila Biddle FA531
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Education and Culture Program, Correspondence of Sheila Biddle
1982-1988
Rockefeller Archive Center
Biddle, Sheila, 1931-
Ford Foundation
FA531
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 standard record storage box.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence
Arrangement
Chronological
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Sheila Biddle worked at the Ford Foundation for more than ten years. From 1982 to 1996, she was a Program Officer in the Foundation's Education and Culture Program. With a focus on higher education, she developed guidelines for the Ford Foundation Fellowship Programs and increased grant support for university African American studies programs.
After leaving the Ford Foundation, Biddle worked as a Senior Research Scholar at Columbia University from 1996 to 2002 and then worked as a consultant on internationalization for different universities and organizations. She earned a Ph.D. in history from Columbia University.
- Chronological Correspondence Mar-Jul 1982, 1982 March-July (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Aug-Oct 1982, 1982 August-October (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Nov-Dec 1982, 1982 November-December (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Jan-Mar 1983, 1983 January-March (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Apr-Jul 1983, 1983 April-July (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Jul 1983, 1983 July (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Aug-Oct 1983, 1983 August-October (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Nov-Dec 1983, 1983 November-December (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Jan-Mar 1984, 1984 January-March (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Apr-Jun 1984, 1984 April-June (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Jul-Sep 1984, 1984 July-September (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Oct-Dec 1984, 1984 October-December (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Jan-Mar 1985, 1985 January-March (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Apr-Jun 1985 (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Jul-Sep 1985, 1985 July-October (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Oct-1985-Oct 1986 (A-K), 1985 October-1986 October (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Oct 1985-Oct 1986 (L-Z) (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Oct 1986-Oct 1987, 1986 October-1987 October (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence Oct 1987-Sep 1988, 1987 October-1988 September (Box 1)